Notify his survivors.
B-E-N-D-E-R
Bender!
Saying B...
E-N...
Der!
Mail call!
Amy, here's your
designer lingerie catalog.
Fry, Sadie's Bra Parade.
And, Leela, Bulk Underpants Outlet.
You buy one pound of underwear
and you're on their list forever.
And for Bender, uh-oh,
a black-bordered envelope.
Oh, no. Someone you know must've died.
I hope it was one of my enemies.
Those guys suck.
Oh, no! My Uncle Vladimir.
Oh, I'm sorry, Bender.
When's the funeral?
Tomorrow, at the family castle.
Followed by the reading of his will.
Well, I'm rich.
Goodbye, losers, whom I've always hated.
Come on. It'll be fun.
Uh, pardon me, my good simpleton.
Could you take us to yon castle?
Castle?
Some say unholy things happen up there.
For example, all of us say that.
Pfft! Superstitious robot mumbo jumbo.
Mumbo, perhaps. Jumbo, perhaps not.
With all your modern science
are you any closer to understanding
the mystery of how a robot walks or talks?
Yes, you idiot.
The circuit diagram is
right here on the inside
of your case.
I choose to believe
what I was programmed to believe.
I will go this far and no further.
And so we commend
Vladimir's remains to the earth.
Filings to filings, rust to rust.
To my loyal butler "you there,"
for his decades of service,
I leave a pittance
to be paid in 20 equal installments
of 1/20th of a pittance each.
To my lazy, spoiled son Tandy,
who never learned the value of a dollar,
I leave my entire $10 million fortune.
Is that a lot?
And to my loving nephew Bender,
assuming he's not responsible
for my death,
I leave my castle.
Yes! Let's stay there tonight.
On condition that he spend
one night within its walls.
Oh, man, there's always a catch!
I get a good vibe from this place.
Nice, long, dinner table.
Quiet, well-behaved spiders.
Graveyard adjacent.
Yep, it's going to be...
What is it?
That painting. The eyes are watching me.
Hmm.
It has motor eye sensors
attached to motion detectors.
So does my butt,
but I don't frame it
and put it on the wall.
Although...
What's that?
I don't know, but it's infectious.
No doubt about it, this place is haunted.
Don't be silly, mon.
The last ghost died over 200 years ago.
The last human ghost, but robot ghosts...
What does it mean?
It's just gibberish.
Uncle Vladimir!
Come, Bender.
You'll like being dead.
That's what they said about being alive.
- Join us.
Join us, Bender.
Oh, my God!
Just as I suspected.
These robots were buried
in improperly shielded coffins.
Their programming leaked
into the castle's wiring
through this old abandoned modem
allowing them to project
themselves as holograms.
Of course! It was so obvious.
Yes, that sequence of words
I said made perfect sense.
We really should tell Bender
there's nothing to be afraid of.
Huh?
No!
Honk! Honk!
Bender, wake up.
He's okay.
Quick, does anyone have any liquor?
Bender, what happened?
Somebody tried to run me over.
And not with a normal hover car.
It crept along the ground
on round rubber feet.
Like a wolf.
Poor Bender, you're seeing things.
You're drinking too much, or too little.
I forget how it works with you.
Anyway, you haven't drunk
exactly the right amount.
Maybe he has.
Look at these tracks.
I think Bender may be telling the truth.
Bender, you look awful.
I prescribe makeup.
Here. It just so happens
I have my Mary Kay sample case.
I just need sleep.
I had nightmares all night
about cars running people over.
Many people dream of a fresh new look.
And Mary Kay can make
those dreams come true.
Look at this!
They found those same rubbery tracks
right here in New New York.
There was a hit-and-run
by the robot porno theater.
Robot porno theater?
I was in that general area last night.
Whoever ran me down out on the moors
must've followed me back here.
Bender, mon,
no one's trying to run you over.
Stop being a big hallucinating baby.
Yeah? Well, could a big
hallucinating baby do this?
I'm scared.
I don't know which I like more,
smashing cars or smashing faces.
Well, lucky you don't
got to decide tonight.
Now, come on, we got church tomorrow.
Did you hear something?
Nah, it was probably
just a golden marmoset.
That don't sound like
no golden marmoset I ever heard.
- Phew!
- Made it.
So, anyway,
what are you wearing tomorrow?
Honk! Honk, honk!
What the...
Transmission fluid?
Where have I been?
What happened?
Gets out of here, youse lousy bum.
Please, I'm scared.
We're all scared.
It's the human condition.
Why do you thinks I put
on this tough-guy façade?
Now, beat it!
I passed out around midnight,
which is much earlier than usual.
And when I woke up,
I found these in my chest cabinet.
Oh, relax, buddy.
You were probably just shooting
some big, fuzzy craps.
No! I think I may have hurt someone.
Oh, Lord, I'm on the verge
of a nervous meltdown.
Geez, Bender, you're scaring me.
You're going wacko.
You're right. I need professional help.
And damn the expense.
Damn the expense!
My friend, you have nothing to worry about
except a nightmarish life
of unremitting horror.
- Phew!
- For, you see, you are a were-car.
A were-car?
The car that ran you down on the moors
was also a were-car.
It beamed the virus to you
through its demonic headlights.
That's crazy.
Yes. So crazy that it must be true.
Each midnight,
when your clock resets to zero,
your hardware reconfigures into
a murderous four-wheeled car.
I can't keep running people over.
I'm not famous enough to get away with it.
Can't you help me?
Yes, but you must be willing
to pay a terrible price.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Follow me.
According to this ancient "read me" file,
your only hope is
to destroy the original were-car.
- I'm with you.
- In its death throes,
the dread car will beam out
the virus's uninstall program.
Thus, ridding you of the curse.
And, otherwise, I can never die?
Who said that? Sure you can die.
You want to die?
No! I want to live.
There's still too many things I don't own.
Then live on, forever cursed.
Each night, your attacks
will become more gruesome.
Until one dark night,
you are doomed to kill
your dearest friend.
I wouldn't want to be me right now.
Now, go! Go!
Uh, could one of you just...
Forget it. I'll just sleep here.
There! No rampaging for you tonight.
Wouldn't it make more sense to weld
everyone except me to the wall?
Just relax, Bender.
Tomorrow, we'll pry you down,
have a nice breakfast
and then go hunt down and slaughter
that ancient evil.
It will be a rich, full day.
Well, good night.
I'm going to go make my dinners
for the next month and freeze them.
Honk! Honk!
Bender, no!
Fry, stay back!
You jerk!
I thought I was your best friend.
What kind of two-timing
kill mobile are you?
Huh?
I can't believe this.
Bender's supposed to murder
his closest friend,
which I thought was me,
but he went straight for you.
He didn't even try
to second-degree murder me.
Could you give me some help?
I think Bender crushed my foot.
Stop rubbing it in.
Oh, God. Fry, I'm so glad to see you.
I didn't hurt you, did I?
Not physically.
But why don't you ask
your new best friend, Leela?
I tried to run you over?
It was very sweet of you, Bender.
Fry, it doesn't mean anything.
I have love enough for two.
Words, nothing but sweet, sweet words
that turn into bitter,
orange wax in my ears.
Enough with the feelings, you two.
If we're going to cure Bender,
we've got to go back to the castle
and hunt down the original were-car.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Cursed, got it.
- Whatever.
The tracks lead here.
Thanks, eagle eye.
Now it's daylight,
so he should be in robot form.
But be careful.
Many robots are stupid and violent.
I wish I was stupid and violent.
Then we'd see what's what.
I'd pound him till I...
Get ye to your houses,
ye ignorant villagers.
Hey!
We are not ignorant villagers.
We're sophisticated New New Yorkers.
Whup his butt!
Stop! What are ye doing?
We're whaling on the original were-car.
Which is you, you jerk.
Ye think me be he?
Sì!
Nee. I mean, no.
I was given the curse many a year ago
while on a bird-watching trip
to the Arctic.
I was attacked
by a vicious motorized sled.
The natives called it
the Abominable Snowmobile.
Yes, it's true.
I ran over that bird-watching jerk,
and a hundred others.
Even my best friend
from aromatherapy school.
I once had a best friend
who liked to smell things with me.
Alas, I'm afraid I'm not
the original were-car.
I received the curse
while taking a learning annex class
from a famous robot actor.
You know him as
Calculon!
Oh, fate most cruel!
Would that my boundless acting skills
might avail me a sword
with which to slay this wretched curse.
Let's kick him some more!
No, wait, let me explain.
It all began one fateful night
a thousand years ago.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're 1,000 years old?
Your bio says you're 27.
Lies! I change my identity
and upgrade my appearance
every few decades to avoid suspicion.
I was all of history's
great acting robots.
Acting Unit 0.8, Thespomat,
David Duchovny.
Look, are you
the original were-car or not?
No, but you are nearing
the end of your search.
For, you see, I was attacked
by the original were-car.
Give us a name, Macbutt!
The year was 2019.
And I was just a lowly robot arm
working in an automotive research lab.
I was working on Project Satan,
a savage, intelligent military vehicle
built from the most evil parts
of the most evil carsin all the world.
The steering wheel
from Hitler's staff car.
The left turn signal
from Charles Manson's VW.
The windshield wipers
from that car that played Knight Rider.
Knight Rider wasn't evil.
His windshield wipers were.
It didn't come up much
in the show, though. Anyway...
Only after bringing Project Satan to life
did they discover
they had made a horrible mistake.
For, you see, it was pure evil.
Honk! Honk!
So what happened to Project Satan?
It's either in Paris, or more likely,
still in the abandoned automotive lab.
You guys distract the were-car
and I'll kill it
by plugging its exhaust pipe
with this silver potato.
Psst! There it is.
It looks so unhappy.
Excuse me, are you Project Satan?
Don't be afraid.
We know what you are.
You do?
Would you like us to
put you out of your misery?
Misery, what misery?
I love killing people.
Squishing them till their organs
squirt out like chunky mustard.
Look, everyone loves killing people.
But I don't want to hurt my friends.
Oh, no! It's midnight!
Hey, this is starting to feel pretty good.
Fry, distract him!
Hey, Project Satan, over here!
I'm a blind pedestrian! 20 points!
Oh, no!
There's no exhaust pipe.
That's right, thanks to
Ed Begley, Jr.'s electric motor.
The most evil propulsion system
ever conceived!
Take whichever one you want.
Oh, boy, I feel like
a car in a candy store.
Yes! He chose me.
He's trying to kill me.
Leela, I'm so happy.
Oh, Thanks, Bender.
Hey, too tight, too tight!
Ooh! Ow!
Whoa!
No! No! No!
Uh-oh.
Bender, you're cured!
But what happened to Fry?
I must have killed him.
He was my best friend, and I killed him.
Oh, I never felt so empty inside.
Bender, I'm alive!
You didn't hurt me at all.
But I know you wanted to,
and that's what matters.
Here's to you.
Hey, that's my last beer, you bastard!
I'll kill you!
I'll kill you, too, buddy.
I'll kill you, too.
Hey!